<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- 
// 
// This is the place for your statements. The maximum 
// number of statements is theoretically unlimited, but
// less then 50 statements are advisable.
// If your are using German Umlauts and other special 
// characters, make sure, that you save this XML-file 
// as an UTF-8-document. White-space inbetween the 
// nodes are ignored. Any white-space within the text-
// nodes, including leading or trailing whitespace and 
// line breaks, is preserved.
//
// EXAMPLE
// Let's define some statements concerning FlashQ:
// Statement 1: FlashQ is very usefull.
// Statement 2: I prefer offline surveys.
// Statement 3: FlashQ is too complicated to configure.
//
// Each statement requires a seperate statement-node 
// consisting out of an opening and a closing tag. The 
// statement itself goes between this two tags. 
// The unique statement id is saved as an 
// attribute called 'id'. We have three exmaple 
// statements and we need therefore three statement-
// nodes and one parent-node. 
//
// <statements version="1.0" htmlparse="false">
//   <statement id="1">FlashQ is very usefull.</statement>
//   <statement id="2">I prefer offline surveys.</statement>
//   <statement id="3">FlashQ is too complicated to configure</statement>
// </statements>
// 
// ===================================================
// 
-->

<statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
	<statement id="1">
		The evidence from rapid reviews is good enough to inform low-risk, emergent policy or decision-making needs when the alternative is the use of no evidence.
	</statement>
	<statement id="2">
		When time allows, a comprehensive systematic review of all available evidence should always be conducted.
	</statement>
	<statement id="3">
		Deviating from accepted systematic review methods may introduce bias and impact the validity of the resulting rapid review, which may be an unacceptable risk for some knowledge users (practitioners).
	</statement>
	<statement id="4">
		Further research comparing the methods and results of rapid reviews and systematic reviews is required before I decide how I feel about rapid reviews.
	</statement>
	<statement id="5">
		Rapid reviews are too focused in scope and/or context to be generalizable to a variety of knowledge users (practitioners).
	</statement>
	<statement id="6">
		Rapid reviews mean different things to different people.
	</statement>
	<statement id="7">
		Rapid reviews should only precede a more comprehensive and rigorous systematic review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="8">
		The opportunity cost of a comprehensive systematic review is too high and it is more advantageous to conduct rapid reviews when timeliness is a factor.
	</statement>
	<statement id="9">
		Rapid reviews do not replace systematic reviews.
	</statement>
	<statement id="10">
		All evidence synthesis products, including rapid reviews and systematic reviews, can be conducted very well or very poorly.
	</statement>
	<statement id="11">
		Rapid reviews are comparable to systematic reviews except they are done in a more timely fashion.
	</statement>
	<statement id="12">
		Rapid reviews are ‘quick and dirty’ systematic reviews.
	</statement>
	<statement id="13">
		Rapid reviews need to be tailored to the specific needs of the knowledge user (practitioners).
	</statement>
	<statement id="14">
		Rapid reviews meet the needs of knowledge users (practitioners).
	</statement>
	<statement id="15">
		There are few evidence on rapid reviews, so I cannot support or oppose their use in decision-making.
	</statement>
	<statement id="16">
		There is so much overlap across the various evidence synthesis methods that I cannot generalize my opinion to favor one over the other without the context of the decision at hand.
	</statement>
	<statement id="17">
		There is a risk involved in tailoring accepted systematic review methods to produce rapid reviews that we do not yet understand.
	</statement>
	<statement id="18">
		Using rapid reviews to inform decisions is better than using no evidence at all.
	</statement>
	<statement id="19">
		It is always appropriate to conduct a rapid review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="20">
		Rapid reviews and all other evidence synthesis products hold the same value as long as they retain the core value of being transparent in conduct, include the highest quality evidence available and present results with a qualification on the strength of evidence.
	</statement>
	<statement id="21">
		Appropriateness of a rapid review varies with the type of decision being made, and any financial, legal or other important contextual facets tied to the decision.
	</statement>
	<statement id="22">
		My confidence in a rapid review is impacted by which methods are tailored to speed up the review process.
	</statement>
	<statement id="23">
		My confidence in a rapid review is directly tied to results being presented and contextualized by the strength and applicability of the evidence.
	</statement>
	<statement id="24">
		It is important to have minimum standards for the methodological conduct of rapid reviews.
	</statement>
	<statement id="25">
		It is important to have minimum standards for the reporting of rapid reviews.
	</statement>
	<statement id="26">
		Standardization of rapid review methods may conflict with the needs of knowledge users (practitioners).
	</statement>
	<statement id="27">
		The value of rapid reviews in the context of emergent decision-making needs outweighs the disadvantages or risk of bias and potentially ‘imperfect’ evidence.
	</statement>-
	<statement id="28">
		Knowledge users don’t always need all of the evidence, they just need the best evidence to support their decision, and what is ‘best evidence’ is specific to the knowledge user (practitioner).
	</statement>
	<statement id="29">
		Knowledge users (practitioners) do not fully understand the implications of streamlining evidence synthesis methods to produce a more timely evidence product.
	</statement>
	<statement id="30">
		Reporting of the results of rapid reviews must be tailored to the knowledge user(s) (practitioners) who commissioned the review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="31">
		Rapid reviews that omit an assessment of the quality of included studies are useless to knowledge users (practitioners).
	</statement>
	<statement id="32">
		Rapid reviews can be timely and valid, even when methodological concessions are made.
	</statement>
	<statement id="33">
		Transparency of process is more important than the actual methods used to produce rapid reviews, as transparency allows the knowledge user (practitioners) to make their own assessment on validity and appropriateness.
	</statement>
	<statement id="34">
		It is appropriate to endeavor to define a single, unique methodology for rapid reviews.
	</statement>
	<statement id="35">
		Rapid reviews are not a unique methodology, they are simply a variation of a systematic review that can fall anywhere on the continuum of evidence synthesis methods.
	</statement>
	<statement id="36">
		The results from a systematic review may not differ from those of a rapid review, but more research is needed to support this theory and quantify why results may be the same or different.
	</statement>
	<statement id="37">
		I put more confidence in evidence produced in a systematic review than of a rapid review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="38">
		The more time spent conducting the review of the evidence, the more valid the results of the review will be.
	</statement>
	<statement id="39">
		Achieving a precise estimate of effect (from a systematic review) may not inform the decision-at-hand any better than a general estimate of effect (produced by a rapid review).
	</statement>
	<statement id="40">
		Rapid reviews should only be conducted when the alternate option is the use of no evidence to inform a decision.
	</statement>
	<statement id="41">
		A well-conducted rapid review may produce better evidence than a poorly conducted systematic review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="42">
		Any review of evidence that takes longer than one month to produce is not a rapid review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="43">
		Any review of evidence that takes longer than two weeks to produce is not a rapid review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="44">
		A rapid review must be justified with a valid rationale for both speeding up the process and tailoring rigourous methods for evidence synthesis.
	</statement>
	<statement id="45">
		A good quality review of evidence is determined by the methods used, not by the speed at which it is completed.
	</statement>
	<statement id="46">
		It is difficult to tell a rapid review from a systematic review unless very specific nomenclature is used in the title or description of methods.
	</statement>
	<statement id="47">
		A rapid review cannot be a systematic review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="48">
		‘Rapid review’ is too broad a phrase—doing a review in a more timely way can only be relative to how long it takes the same team to produce a full systematic review.
	</statement>
	<statement id="49">
		Producers (researchers) are more concerned with the methodology and validity of rapid reviews than knowledge users (practitioners).
	</statement>
	<statement id="50">
		It is difficult to judge the validity of a rapid review as the reporting is often truncated and protocols are not published.
	</statement>
</statements>